Well, this week has been a fun one in
the world of AI. We had the release of
Nano Banana, the best AI image editor
we've ever seen, some very unlikely
partnerships between companies that no
one saw coming, and an innovative way to
help content creators make money when AI
cites them as a source. All that and
more in today's deep dive. I don't want
to waste your time, so let's get right
into it. Starting with the fact that
Nano Banana has finally been unpeeled.
Oh, brother. This guy stinks.
That's right. We finally got public
access to Nano Banana and they actually
made it free. Now, the official name is
Gemini Flash 2.5 image. Yeah, Google's
not the best at naming.
You suck.
So, pretty much everybody still just
calls it Nano Banana. Now, this isn't
the first time I talked about Nano
Banana. It's not the second time I've
talked about it. It's actually the third
time and I've showed off a lot of
examples already of what this image
model is capable of. But since I showed
those off, there has been so many other
cool use cases that have popped up that
I want to share with you. But to show
you what it does quickly, you upload an
image, you tell it you want to be a
matador or an artist, and it literally
changes the image to whatever you tell
it to. This is something that could
potentially replace Photoshop for very
simple edits, honestly. And again, I
don't want to go too deep into this
because I have done two other videos
where we did all sorts of demonstrations
on what it's capable of, but this is
really cool. My buddy Balav Sudu, he
shared this over on X. Since Nano Banana
has Gemini's world knowledge, you can
just upload screenshots of the real
world and ask it to annotate stuff for
you. You are a location-based AR
experience generator. Highlights points
of interest in the image and annotate
relevant information about it. And then
HBT
here said, "And you can combine it with
3D grid-like wireframe mesh prompts."
So, this is something I really want to
try here. So, here I am inside of Google
Earth. I've zoomed in on Petgo Park here
in San Diego. If I flip this around, you
can see there's the bay, there's the
convention center. So, let's go ahead
and screenshot this here. And then we'll
jump into Google AI Studio over at a
studio.google.com.
up on the top right. We want to make
sure this is set on Gemini 2.5 flash
image preview as we can see aka nano
banana. So we've got our image here.
Let's grab our prompt from Bavl here.
You are a location-based AR experience
generator. Highlight Petco Park in this
image and annotate relevant information
about it. After 15 seconds, here's what
it gave us. So it highlighted Petco Park
for some reason. It also highlighted a
hotel next to Petco Park, but it did
give some information. Open 2004,
capacity 40,209. I'm assuming that's
correct. Sounds about right. But that's
not the only cool new use case that I've
come across. Here's another one from
Harsh here where they gave it this image
of what looks like Google Maps and said
they asked it to draw the ground view of
the red pin and it showed this image
here. I'm going to take this image that
we just created and let's see if we can
leverage this same technique. I'm going
to crop in a little bit to get rid of
all the Google Earth stuff. So, here's
our image. And then let's go ahead and
add a star. We'll make it red and we'll
fill it in red. Then I'll just put it
right here. And then we'll tell it to
find the view from the star. Pull the
image back in. Give me an image of the
ground view from the perspective of the
red star looking at Petco Park. Now,
that's a little bit further away than
where I dropped this star. It should be
a little bit closer. It's still pretty
impressive to me that it could even do
this at all. I mean, but we do have
Google Earth, so if you did want this
same thing. You don't need to use Gemini
for it. I just thought it was cool that
it's capable of it. Someone here shared
that they restored the first photograph
ever taken with Nano Banana. So, this
was the first photograph ever. And
here's what Nano Banana gave them back
based on what it understood from the
image. Here's another one from Har
prompt. make image daytime and isometric
temple only. So they took this picture
of the temple and then had it do this
isometric drawing of it. Here's another
one where they took a picture of this
building and had it draw an isometric
picture of the building. Super super
impressive. And you don't just have to
use Nano Banana with Google either. It's
being rolled out into like every
platform out there. Higsfield has it.
Crea has it. Scenario has it. You know
what? I'm not going to list them all.
pretty much every platform out there has
rolled nano banana into it. Leonardo is
also getting it soon. The evidence being
this email where they put bananas and
everything. But the one that fascinated
me the most was the fact that Adobe
Firefly got Nano Banana. And the reason
it fascinated me was well because
they're the company that makes Adobe
Photoshop and they also have their own
AI models that they've been trying to
promote. You know, the Firefly models.
But now you can use Nano Banana directly
inside of the various Firefly products.
It really makes me wonder if Adobe is
starting to kind of realize that maybe
they shouldn't be in the foundation
model game and building their own models
and maybe they should just leverage the
models that are out there being built by
companies like Google and OpenAI and
Runway etc. Because first they rolled
out V3 into their video generation
model. So if you want to generate videos
with Firefly, you can use Firefly or you
can use V3. And now they rolled out Nano
Banana into Firefly. So you can use
their Firefly image models or you can
use Google's Nano Banana. And you can
even use it for free here. As soon as I
log in, it says try Google Gemini 2.5
Flash image model in Firefly on us.
Unlimited access to Google 2.5 flash
image model. So inside of Firefly here,
you've got general settings. And not
only is Gemini 2. Flash image in here,
it's set to the default. So even above
all of the Firefly models that are in
here, the GPT image model, the Flux, the
runways, all of these models, the
default model is a Google model. It's
not even Adobe's model, but it works
just the same. Drop an image in. I'll
use this one that we've played with in
the past, and I'll tell it change all
the Mountain Dew bottles to bananas. And
just like in AI Studio, it does what you
ask it to. I mean, it missed one of the
Mountain Dew bottles, but I'll let it
go. Another big update out of Google
this week is there's now AI powered live
translation as well as a new language
learning tool directly inside of Google
Translate. So, if you ever need to
communicate with somebody in another
language, you can do it in real time now
with the Translate app.
Hi there. Um, my friend told me there's
a sandwich here that's really good, but
I'm not sure which one it is. It's
spicy, has really tasty cheese on it and
avocados, I think.
I think I know what it is. It's
seasonal. In fact, we've already taken
it off the menu, but let me see if we
can still prepare it for you. It's
delicious.
On top of that, they've also added a
language learning feature where you can
actually use the translate app to try to
learn other languages. You tell it how
good you are at the language already. It
creates scenarios for you and it gives
you little exercises to best learn
whatever language you're trying to learn
here. So, it seems like now Google is
becoming a direct competitor with
Dolingo. Now, let's stick with Google
just for a minute here because they also
rolled out some new updates to their
vids platform. Now, they have VO3 which
is their generative video platform. You
give it a prompt, it generates a video
based on that prompt and it sort of like
makes animations or real world video.
Vids is more like you give it a prompt
and it makes like a PowerPoint
presentation style video. We've demoed
it in previous videos before, but now
they're actually sort of merging VO3
into it. You can see in this little
screenshot here that you can actually
have AI video clips within your Vids
videos. Now, here's an example where
they take one of the slides and then
they grab the image of the shoe that's
in the slide and then they actually
generate an animation of the shoe that
then goes back onto the slide. So now
when they play their video that looks
like a PowerPoint presentation, it
actually has animations in it on top of
like the types of slides that it shows.
They also added the ability to put AI
generated avatars directly inside of
your presentation. So you can select
from their avatars. I don't believe you
can upload yourself yet, but you can
pick from the avatars that they created.
Give it some dialogue and it will
actually lip-s sync it up and you could
put it in your video.
Welcome to the Symbol Outdoor Goods
product support page. We're here to help
address common questions about the
latest product in our line of camping
essentials, our new solar powered
flashlight. They also added a feature
where you can generate a transcript
based on the video that you created and
then once it's created the transcript,
you can actually clean it up and it will
remove the ums and the h from your video
and then you can actually edit the video
by simply editing the transcript. You
can delete portions of the transcript
and it will delete those portions of the
video. If you've used Descript at all
before, well, they're now kind of going
head-to-head with Descript because
that's something that we've seen in
Descript for quite a while and now
they're just making it available for
people who use Vids. And if you're
interested in Vids, well, all of the
really cool features are on the paid
plan. You have to be a business or
enterprise starter customer, Google AI
Pro or Ultra subscriber, or have a
Workspace for Education account. But it
does say the basic Vids editor without
Gemini is available to all consumers. So
you can use Vids. You just don't get all
the cool AI features we just showed off.
You know what the hardest part about
keeping up with AI is? It moves way too
fast. Just blink for a second and
there's a brand new model like a crazy
tool launch or some company making
headlines for all the wrong reasons.
Most people simply don't have the time
to track it all. And that's why for this
video I partnered with myself. Well, the
Future Tools newsletter. It's completely
free, goes out twice a week, and it's
basically your shortcut to staying ahead
of the AI curve. Every Wednesday and
Friday, I round up the biggest AI news,
the most useful new tools, and the
stories that actually matter without you
needing to doom scroll X or dig through
a 100 blogs. And here's the best part.
When you sign up today, you instantly
get free access to the AI income
database. It's a giant resource that
shows you dozens of different ways
people are making money with AI,
complete with the methods, the process,
and the exact tools you need to try it
yourself. Totally free just for
subscribing. So, if you're into AI tech,
or just don't want to fall behind, head
on over to futuretools.io, drop in your
email, and you'll be plugged into the
smartest corner of the AI world. Thank
you so much to me for sponsoring this
video. Now, let's get back to it. All
right, so moving on. I've got to be
honest here. I actually don't know when
this feature rolled out. I sort of
missed the launch announcement of it,
but Cling has a first and last frame
ability where you can give it the first
frame and the last frame and it will try
to animate all of the stuff that's in
between the frames. I learned about this
from my buddy Tim at Theoretically Media
and he showed off some examples of how
good this actually is. Give it one frame
at the beginning, one frame at the end,
and it figures out what's supposed to go
in the middle. One thing I haven't
really been impressed with so far is I
haven't been able to get a video that
starts with my face and then ends with a
wolf and it makes it look like I'm
merging into the wolf, like a werewolf
or like anomorphs. So, I'm going to log
into my Cling account here and I will
come over to video and we can see we've
got add start frame, add end frame.
Here's an image of me kind of like
squatting down. Maybe that'll make it
easier since I'm already sort of low to
the ground. Let's see what happens.
We'll add that as the start frame. I'll
grab this image of a wolf here that I
made in Leonardo and we'll set that as
the end frame. Let's go ahead and for
our prompt, we'll do the man slowly
morphs into a wolf. Let's generate that.
And here's the output we got from it.
Complete with sound and everything.
Not bad at all. This is probably the
best sort of morph video like this that
I've seen. I think it kind of helped
that I was already sort of like bent
over in the image. So, you could see I
just squat down into like a wolf
position and then yeah, it morphs into a
wolf just like it should. Probably the
most impressive start frame, end frame
video tool I've seen so far. Cling has
always really kind of impressed me
though. Hun has just rolled out a new
upgrade as well with its new Avatar 4.
So, the digital twins that you create
with Hey, Jen are supposedly a lot more
realistic. It says, "Your digital twin
now mirrors your gestures, expressions,
and mannerisms, adapts to your script,
speaking every line how you would, moves
like you naturally from head to toe, and
feels unmistakably you and not AI. I
want to try this out myself." So, I just
uploaded a brand new video that I just
recorded. It's 6% ready, and after about
4 minutes or so, it's ready to check it
out. Let's see what we got. Hey Matt
Wolf, your digital twin is ready. Try
creating videos with it. Also, click the
feedback button to share what you think.
Hope you enjoy. I don't feel like what I
got is a whole lot better than what I
normally get, but that may have just
been the demo video that it gave me. So,
let's go ahead and make sure we've got
Avatar 4 selected here at the top. And I
will give it a quick script. And after
about 5 minutes, let's see what we got.
Slow internet, stale air. Why suffer
through either when you can fix both?
Introducing the scented Wi-Fi router.
The world's first router that streams
blazing fast internet and fills your
home with delightful aromomas. Setup is
easy. Just plug it in, pick your Wi-Fi
password and your fragrance. Vanilla
vibes, pine forest, pizza night, you
name it, we've got it. I mean, the lip
syncing is a lot better than it used to
be, but it's the voice. I I just don't
feel like the voice is realistic enough
still. It still just feels like an AI
voice to me, but it's lip-s synced a lot
better and has a lot less like
abnormalities in there. I used to have
issues with the beard where it looked
like there was like hair going over my
teeth and stuff like that and it always
messed up on the beard. And it's
definitely got that kind of stuff dialed
in, but that voice, that robotic AI
voice is just still not doing it for me.
But definitely give it a try. They do
have other ways to do the voice. So, if
I went to create video here up under
voice, they do have advanced settings
where you can use like 11 Labs or 11
Labs V3. So, you can actually get that
voice dialed in a little bit better, but
the one that's directly out of Hey Gen
right now, I don't know. It's just still
not doing it for me. Along similar
lines, we got a new open model called
Juan S2V. This is a model where you give
it an image input and you give it an
audio input and it will actually sync
and animate the video based on the audio
like this. I have been second to Joe my
whole life in everything and I will not
be the person you settle for just
because you cannot have her.
And you can see that there's emotion in
the face and there's a lot of movement
and even this side character here that
she's talking to is moving a little bit.
Very, very impressive. Now, there is a
hugging face space where you can try
this model out as well as a model scope
studio. Unfortunately, I went and tried
to use the hugging face space and it
said it was going to take about 4 hours
to generate it. So yeah, I'm not demoing
that one right now. I am attempting it
in the model scope studio, but even this
one is claiming it's going to take like
almost 30 minutes to generate. So I
would love to actually show a test that
I did myself, but these servers are
overwhelmed. And when I tried
duplicating the spaces, it didn't work
because you need an API key that I don't
have. And so, yes, it's publicly
available, but if you want to use this,
you probably want to download it on
GitHub and try to run it locally. It
does say it should be able to work on a
computer with a 4080. And along similar
lines, this week, we got a product
called LipSync 2 Pro from this company,
Sync Labs, and it's a state-of-the-art
video model that edits what anyone says
in a video. So, you give it a video and
then you could give it like a different
set of audio and it will change the
audio and the lip-s syncing in the video
to whatever the uploaded audio is. So,
if I head over to sync.so, I can
actually drag in an MP4 here. Let me
grab one of just like me on camera. So,
I'm uploading a short 55 second video.
It's actually a video of me doing an
intro for one of my podcast episodes.
And then I can drag a different audio
file in here. I'm going to drag and drop
a little Rick Morty soundbite in here
and let's see if this works.
You have my word as a caregiver.
Everything's going to be fine.
I mean, yeah, it it worked, but I'm
running into that issue where you could
tell the mustache is sort of making it a
little weird. I don't know what it is
with AI video generators and beards and
mustaches, but they always seem to like
make everything look a little wonky. As
with almost every week, we have some
fresh drama in the AI world.
We've got Elon Musk's XAI company suing
Apple and Open AI over AI competition.
Another one.
Basically, Elon is claiming that the
Apple store is being more favorable to
OpenAI than X and helping boost tools
like OpenAI to the top of the downloads
list while ignoring X. So he thinks that
Apple is treating X unfairly compared to
OpenAI. And I don't know if you
remember, but for several weeks in a
row, we talked about how Meta was
poaching a whole bunch of people from
various companies like OpenAI and Apple
and Enthropic to build their super
intelligence team. Well, it didn't take
long before people started jumping ship
from Meta and going back to their
original job. This week, two prominent
AI researchers left Meta's super
intelligence labs just weeks after
coming on board. AI Verma and Ethan
Knight both spent less than a month at
Meta before going back to their jobs at
OpenAI. Shia Nyak, who also was leading
generative AI efforts over at Meta, is
also leaving Meta to go to OpenAI. So, I
don't know what's going on over at Meta.
They went and promised tons of money to
these people and built this super
intelligence team and slowly but surely,
like before they even have a chance to
get started, they're all kind of
dropping off. And there's been a lot of
other AI news this week. I covered all
the really cool stuff that you can
actually take action on and use right
now today. But there's a lot more I want
to cover. So, let's jump into a rapid
fire section.
This week, XAI opensourced their Gro 2.5
model. If you're keeping track, they're
currently on Grock 4. So, this is kind
of like two model generations ago for
Grock. And apparently Elon's starting a
new division or something of XAI to
build a purely AI software company
called Macrohard. Yes, that is like I
guess the opposite of Microsoft. He
says, "Yes, it's a tongue-in-cheek name,
but the project is very real. In
principle, given that software companies
like Microsoft do not themselves
manufacture any physical hardware, it
should be possible to simulate them
entirely with AI." Now, I'm a little
confused by this because I thought
Microsoft did sell hardware. I mean, I
guess maybe they don't manufacture the
hardware, but they do sell hardware.
Like, the Microsoft Surface computers
and tablets are a thing. I also went and
toured their quantum lab last time I was
in Seattle and saw the Maharana chip
that's used for quantum computing. But I
mean, I guess Microsoft doesn't
physically manufacture them in their own
factories here in the US. All that to
say, I have no freaking clue what his
plans with macro hard is. I don't know
what he's trying to build. I'm guessing
like their cloud services like Microsoft
Azure, which a lot of companies run on.
Maybe that's what he's trying to clone.
I have no idea. Moving on to the
opposite of macro hard. Microsoft this
week rolled out two new in-house AI
models, MAI Voice 1 and MAI1 Preview.
MAI Voice 1 is their first highly
expressive natural speech generation
model, and they've been testing MAI1
Preview over on LM Arena. So, MAI1
Preview appears to be a language model
that uses a mixture of experts. Don't
know a ton about this one yet, but
apparently if you want to go use Ella
Marina, you can test it out. And here's
a quick demo of what their AI voice
model sounds like.
On a sunny afternoon, a spirited
four-year-old named Jamie approached a
grizzled pirate.
Under a sprawling Texas sky, a skeptical
cowboy, and an enthusiastic techie met
outside a diner.
You can try it inside of Copilot Labs.
copilot.microsoft.com/labsauudioexpression
with different modes like emotive and
story various voices and different
styles so you can make it sound sad or
joyous or curious or excited. I'm going
to use the emotive mode voice teak style
encouragement. Let's see what it sounds
like.
Listen, I totally get it. Slow internet,
stale air. Who wants to deal with that?
But guess what? You don't have to suffer
through either of those things anymore.
I mean, seriously, let me introduce you
to something that's just incredible. The
Scented Wi-Fi router. Can you believe
it? It's the world's first router that
not only gives you blazing fast
internet, but also fills your home with
the most delightful aromomas. What's
crazy about that is it did sound really
good and natural, but it added a whole
bunch of stuff. Like, this was the
dialogue I gave it, and it just went off
on its own tangents and added a whole
bunch of extra words and sentences in
there. So, pretty interesting. But I
think that also really adds to the sort
of realism that comes out of it. And
while we're talking about AI voice,
OpenAI rolled out a new feature for
developers inside of their API. It's
called GPT Realtime and Realtime API for
production voice agents. And it's
basically that voice mode that you get
inside of the chat GPT app where you can
have a conversation with it, but that's
available in the API. So you can bake
that into like your own apps. Now,
Perplexity this week introduced Comet
Plus, which is a new subscription that
allows users to get access to premium
content from trusted publishers and
journalists. So, if you have an iPhone,
you know how you have the Apple News and
you can actually pay a subscription for
Apple News and it gets you access to
like a whole bunch of different news
resources that are included in Apple
News. Well, Perplexity Comet is
basically doing that. But what's really
interesting to me about this is this
section, the business model for the AI
age. Comet Plus subscribers gain access
to the sites and content of
participating publishers. In exchange,
we're distributing all of that revenue
to participating publishers minus a
small portion for Perplexity's compute
costs. Comet Plus is the first
compensation model that allocates
revenue to our partners based on three
types of internet traffic: human visits,
search citations, and agent actions.
Publishers should settle for nothing
less. The revenue allocation recognizes
the reality that users now choose how
they want to consume information.
Browsing manually, asking for AI
generated answers, or deploying agents
for complex tasks. Publishers deserve
compensation that matches this new
reality. And I totally applaud this.
Like this is what we need to see more of
an AI. This is the type of thing that is
going to get content creators and
publishers and news outlets finally on
board with AI and these companies
scraping their AI information. They want
to be compensated for their work. AI is
really, really rapidly taking the
incentives out of content creation. If
people make content, they want to get
traffic to their website so they can put
ads on it or sell them a membership or
sell them products or sell them
affiliate links or whatever. They want
you on their website reading the content
because that's how they make their
money. And AI is taking your content and
just putting it in an answer to a
prompt, whether it's on Google or
ChatgBT or Perplexi or any of these
platforms. They're taking that content
and just putting it in front of you. And
it's really disincentivizing people from
wanting to create new content. And I
think things like this need to happen.
This is where we need to go with AI and
the way they scrape AI. Compensate the
sources of the content somehow. And
Perplexity is trying. And I really,
really appreciate that. As we can see
here from their little chart, 80% of the
revenue is going to go to the
publications. Now, right now, we're just
talking big publications. I don't know
exactly which publications, but like I
imagine New York Times, Wall Street
Journal, Wired, places like that that
have kind of paywalled content. You
could pay a Perplexity subscription and
get access to this content that would
normally be paywalled. But I do see this
going in the direction of being opened
up to more sort of independent content
creators down the line as well. So, a
really, really exciting start to
something that I think inevitably needs
to happen. And while we're on the topic
of AI and agentic browsers, Anthropic is
rolling out a Chrome extension. And the
idea is it wants to do a lot of that
agentic browsing and using AI in your
browser, but it wants to do it directly
in your real browser. So, we've seen
like OpenAI's operator where you give it
a prompt and it goes and does the
agentic work, but it does it like on a
cloud computer on a cloud browser. So,
it's not doing anything on your computer
or directly inside of your browser.
Enthropic is testing out literally
letting AI control your browser, moving
your mouse, typing things for you,
navigating websites for you, purchasing
things for you directly in your browser.
Now, most people don't have access to
this yet. They're rolling it out to a
thousand beta testers. You can get on a
wait list to try it out, but I have no
idea if this is going to get fully
rolled out or not. I guess it kind of
depends on what the testers results are
from it. This is one of the craziest
things I've seen this week outside of
Nano Banana, and that's Craya's new
realtime video generation model. This
isn't public yet. I got on the wait
list. I'm hoping to play with it soon,
but this looks really cool. You can
actually control what's happening in the
video in real time. You can see on the
left they've got like an image version
and on the right there's a video but the
video is changing based on what's going
on in the image and it's actually a
video. Like Korea already had this
feature rolled out for images but now
they've got it for video and it looks
really impressive. Like I don't know if
you're going to be able to key frame it.
I would imagine that would be the way to
do it is you kind of make the image the
way you want it to start and then you
kind of move it in a different direction
and key frame it. And ideally, you can
make videos using like uh some sort of
key frame system. I don't know how it
works yet. I don't have access, but it
looks really, really impressive.
Notebook LM got another update this
week. It's now available in 80 different
languages. So, if you speak a language
that Notebook LM didn't used to work
with, well, it probably does now.
I am fluent in over
6 million.
This was a partnership I never saw
coming. Apparently, Midjourney is
partnering with Meta. Alexander Wang,
who's the head of the super intelligence
group over at Meta and the founder of
Scale AI, he said on X, "Today, we're
proud to announce a partnership with
Midjourney to license their aesthetic
technology for our future models and
products, bringing beauty to billions."
So, Meta has their own image generator.
It's called Emu. You can go and use it
inside of any of the Meta Messenger
platforms and generate images. But
similar to how I was talking earlier
about how Adobe is starting to use like
Google's models and Flux models and
OpenAI models and you can start to use
all these other models inside the
platform. It seems like Meta might be
going in that direction with their
platforms as well. Maybe they don't want
to pursue image and video models as hard
as they used to. So let's go partner
with MidJourney who's already kind of
cracked the code and put those models
inside of our platforms. That's what it
feels like. It'll be really, really
interesting to see how this plays out.
Midjourney's been notorious for not
integrating into anything else. The only
way to use Midjourney is in Discord or
on their website, and there's no API.
You can't use it in any other platforms.
Any other platform that claims, hey, you
can generate with Midjourney in our
platform without having to pay
Midjourney's fees. They're lying.
They're they created a model that looks
similar to MidJourney, but they're not
actually using Midjourney. Midjourney is
connected to nobody, which makes it so
shocking that Meta is the company they
decide to go and partner with. Here's an
interesting one as well. YouTube has
been secretly using AI to edit people's
videos. So, apparently, people were just
uploading their regular videos to
YouTube and behind the scenes, YouTube
was going and using AI to try to make
them look better, to like upscale them
and make them look a little more
polished. And people started to notice
and did not like it at all. People
started getting comments from others
going, "Hey, is this AI generated?" And
the creator was like, "No, it's not AI
generated." And they go look at their
video and they'd be like, "What the
hell? Why does my video look AI
generated?" It was because YouTube was
sort of doing stuff behind the scenes to
apparently improve the video quality.
And sort of related, I don't know if
you've seen this whole thing with the
Will Smith video, but this video has
been going around and people have been
saying, "Is Will Smith really making AI
generated videos of crowds and fans?" I
mean, just this little still image here,
you can see he's got this like frowny
sad face that looks very AI. These
people's hands are like merging
together. And if we take a closer look
at the video here, I'm going to kind of
scrub through it here and stop on some
shots. Like here's another one where if
I freeze frame it, some of these faces
look very like AI. And so people were
accusing Will Smith of putting out a
video with a lot of AI clips to make it
look like he had big crowds and lots of
fans out at his show. I mean, look at
this kid with the Raiders hat. Does that
look like it actually says Raiders on
it? Here's another freeze frame that
just if you look at the people's faces,
it looks very AI, but apparently this
video is not AI. Says these fans aren't
fake. It was pointed out that Will Smith
has posted photos and videos throughout
his tour that show some of the same fans
and some of the same footage. We can see
here in this article from The Verge, it
says, "It's bad timing for Smith.
YouTube had recently begun testing a
feature that would use traditional
machine learning technology to unblur,
dn noiseise, and improve clarity. These
edits made YouTube short look even more
fake than the videos on other platforms.
They did share that you'll be able to
opt out of this on YouTube if you want,
but they haven't rolled that feature out
yet. So, supposedly Will Smith put out
this video. They used AI to try to like
clean it up and make it look better. I
don't know if Will Smith's team did it
or it was the YouTube algorithm thing
that did it, but either way, they tried
to use AI to improve the video, which
just made the whole video look fake and
spread accusations and rumors that Will
Smith was making AI generated videos of
his fans and crowds. But the actual
truth is, I don't know. I'm I'm I'm sure
this was real footage, but it was
touched up with AI, which just made it
look very very AI. And in the absolute
best story of the week and the final
story of today's video, a baby in
Colombia was registered with the name
Chat Yippity, a name that was inspired
by Chat GPT. So, if you're looking for
the next hot baby name for your kid and
you can't decide, well, maybe go with
Chat Yippity for your next kid. I mean,
maybe my third kid will be Chat Yippity
Wolf. We'll see. No, I don't have a kid
on the way if you're wondering. But
that's what I got for you today. Thank
you so much for tuning in and nerding
out and having fun with me with all of
this AI stuff. It's always a blast. I
love getting to make these videos for
you. This has been an absolute dream
come true that my life now is playing
with AI toys and then turning around and
sharing all the AI toys and news with
you. And I couldn't be more grateful and
appreciative that you choose to spend
all this time with me learning about
what's going on in the AI world. I do
not take that for granted. And I really
really appreciate every single one of
you that tunes in and leaves comments
and likes and subscribes and does all
this stuff. I really really appreciate
you. Thank you once again for tuning in.
Hopefully I'll see you in the next one.
Bye-bye. Thank you so much for nerding
out with me today. If you like videos
like this, make sure to give it a thumbs
up and subscribe to this channel. I'll
make sure more videos like this show up
in your YouTube feed. And if you haven't
already, check out futuretools.io where
I share all the coolest AI tools and all
the latest AI news. And there's an
awesome free newsletter. Thanks again.
Really appreciate you.